女士们 先生们 机长刚打开了 系好安全带的指示灯
ladies and gentlemen,the captain has turned on the seat belt sign.
请回到座位 系好安全带 直到指示灯熄灭...
Please return to your seats with your seat belts fastened until the captain turns off the light
可以安全的在机舱走动为止
and it is safe to move about the cabin.
我可不想就这么死了
I don't want to die this way.
你怎么能那么镇定?
How can you be so calm?
机翼都快从机身上抖下去了
The wings are gonna rip right off this tin can.
没事的
It's all right.
这种气流不会引起飞机结构损坏
There's no correlation between air turbulence and structural failure unless,
当然了 我们正在雷暴区域中
of course,we're flying inside a thunderstorm.
我们正冲破两股不同气流阻碍
We're just crossing a barrier between different air currents.
你是干嘛的 火箭专家吗?
What are you,a rocket scientist?
犯罪现场调查员
Crime scene investigator.
你尽量别去想这颠簸就好了
Just try not to think about the turbulence.
你是做什么的 先生...
What do you do for a living,Mr...
我叫Riley, Ed Riley
Riley-- Ed Riley.
我是发明家
Inventor.
我今天是去华盛顿申请专利的
I'm filing a patent in DC today.
不管是跑 游泳 睡觉 跳伞 还是空难...
Run,swim,sleep,skydive,crash in an airplane...
这东西绝不会脱落
no way this is coming off.
我称其为"假发之锁"
I call it the "The Wig Lock."
25%的年轻人在二十几岁时都经历过脱发
25% percent of all young men in their 20s suffer from it.
我28岁开始脱发的
Started losing my hair when I was 28.
我知道你可能在想 这家伙那么年轻毛囊就出问题了
Now,I know what you're thinking: this guy's too young to be follicly challenged.
早期男性脱发是我家族遗传
Premature male baldness runs in my family.
主要是我妈妈那边的基因
Actually,it's on my mother's side.
她的四个兄弟...
All four of her brothers...
都在40岁之前秃顶了
bald before they reached 40.
我还不知道你叫什么呢
I didn't catch your name.
Mac Taylor
Uh,Mac Taylor.
呃...我离开一下
Uh...excuse me one minute.
不好意思 先生 请您回到座位上去
I'm sorry,sir,I'll have to ask you to return to your seat.
我是纽约犯罪实验室的Taylor警探
Detective Taylor,New York Crime Lab.
发生什么事了?
Is there a problem?
谁发现他的?
Who found him?
我
I did.
飞机颠簸时 我看到血从门缝里流出来
During the turbulence,I saw blood coming from under the door.
伤在颈动脉要害
Severed carotid artery.
他被捅了
He was stabbed.
你发现什么和此事有关的线索吗?
Did you find or see anything that could have caused this?
没有
Nothing.
有什么人在尸体被发现前 或之后进过洗手间?
What about anyone leaving or entering the bathroom before the body was discovered?
没有
No.
联邦空中警察
Federal Air Marshal.
他的枪不见了
His gun is gone.
你觉得凶手是想劫机吗?
You think his killer's gonna take over the plane?
他干掉了唯一可能阻止他的人
He disarmed the only person who could stop him.
CSI:纽约篇 第五季 第3集 Turbulence
CSI:NY SEASON 05  EPISODE 03
打开系好安全带的指示灯 通知飞行员锁好驾驶舱
Keep the seat belt sign on and notify the pilots to stay locked inside the cockpit
我们飞回纽约肯尼迪机场
and get us turned around back to JFK.
你觉得劫机的人可能不止一个吗?
Do you think there's more than one hijacker?
不清楚
I don't know.
如果我们飞回去 乘客会问很多问题
If we turn around,people are gonna start asking questions.
告诉乘客有人生病了
Tell the passengers someone is sick.
给我拿一个急救箱 还有乘客名单
I'm gonna need a first aid kit and the passenger manifest.
你们都回去工作
The rest of you,back to work.
像往常一样
Business as usual.
如果有人要用洗手间 请他们用前面的
If anyone needs to use the bathroom,have them use the one up front.
别让任何人过来了
I want no one back here.
记住 这架飞机上的某个人就是凶手
Remember,someone on this plane is a killer.
女士们 先生们 我们遇到了紧急情况
Ladies and gentlemen,we have an emergency.
有一位乘客需要就医 我们按指示返回纽约
A passenger is ill,and we have been instructed to return to New York.
请大家回到座位上 全程系好安全带
Please take your seats and remain seated for the duration of our flight.
给您带来的不便 我们深表歉意
We apologize for this inconvenience.
你听到了吗? 有乘客生病了
Did you hear that? A passenger's sick.
实际上意思是一个引擎不行了
Yeah,right,what they really mean is an engine is about to fail.
这事和一个乘客有关
This is about a passenger.
他死了
He's dead.
什么?
What?
我需要你帮忙
I'm gonna need your help.
你得保持镇定
You've got to stay calm.
机上发生谋杀了
There's been a murder on board.
凶手还有枪
Whoever did it has a gun.
你不是开玩笑吧?
You're not joking,are you?
你跟我到机舱后面来
You're gonna follow me to the back of the plane.
我希望你站在厨房里 观察机舱内可疑的动静
I want you to stand in the galley,keep your eyes on the cabin and look for anything suspicious.
比如什么?
Like what?
你看到就知道了
You'll know it when you see it.
为什么找我?
Why me?
你是唯一一个我确定不是凶手的人
You're the only one I'm sure is not the killer.
你全程都坐在我旁边
You were next to me the entire flight.
噢 天哪
Oh,boy.
这人真是死了
That guy's dead,all right.
不过头发还蛮漂亮的
Nice hair,though.
你帮我盯着
You're my eyes.
保证大家都在座位上 发现可疑的 就告诉我
Keep them on the cabin; you see something you don't like,let me know.
警探 急救箱和乘客名单
First aid kit and passenger manifest,Detective.
钱包和身份证都不见了
No wallet or ID.
没有带照片的证件
Nothing with a picture.
可能他把钱包留在座位上了
Maybe he left his wallet in his seat.
他坐哪里?
What seat was he in?
我记得是...6C
I think it was... 6C.
但是名单上没人坐那排
No one listed on the manifest for that row.
空警不一定都订座的
Well,air marshals aren't always assigned seats.
不过肯定是第6排
But it was definitely row six.
我记得起飞之后给他拿过杂志
I remember giving him a magazine right after we took off.
我去看看他的座位
I'll check his seat.
同时 你去联系一下联邦空中法警局
And while I do that,have the captain contact the Federal Air Marshal Service.
告诉他们警号
Give them that badge number.
要一些这个人的资料来
Let's see what they can tell us about this guy.
根据乘客名单 James Turner应该坐在11D
According to the manifest,seat 11D is supposed to be occupied by James Turner.
确实有人坐过那里
There was a gentleman sitting there.
还没开始餐饮服务 我看到他焦躁不安 就给他拿了杯水
Beverage service hadn't started,but he seemed very agitated,so I gave him some water.
我不知道他去了哪里
I don't know where he went.
在那呢
There he is.
12排
Row 12.
你有什么发现吗?
You find anything?
没有
Nothing.
没有钱包 没有随身行李
No wallet,no carry-on.
有麻烦了
We have a problem.
据联邦空中法警局的资料
According to the Federal Air Marshal Service,
这个警号应该是Roger Stockwell的
this badge number is registered to a guy named Roger Stockwell.
将近50岁 身材不高 头发斑白了
Late 40s,short,cropped salt-and-pepper hair,
本来今天应该飞去洛杉矶的
and scheduled to be on a flight to Los Angeles today.
不怎么像这位死者
Not the description of our vic.
那这人是谁呢?
Then,who's this guy?
我可以把他的指纹拍照发回实验室
I can send a picture of his prints back to my lab,but,uh...
但是我得用手机
I'm gonna need cell phone service.
驾驶舱里机长有卫星电话
The captain has a satellite phone in the cockpit.
上面也有摄像头的
I believe it has a camera.
去拿过来
Get it.
我还需要一个唇膏和三个呕吐袋
I also need a tube of lipstick and three air sickness bags.
我去拿呕吐袋
I'll collect the barf bags.
拿来了
I got it.
这是飞行员的卫星电话
Here's the pilot's satellite phone.
拿着这个
Hold that.
打得不错啊
Impressive.
嘿
Hey.
只是热身呢 Walsh
Just warming up,Walsh.
你还挺爱现呢 Bonasera
You're a show-off,Bonasera.
不是吧
Nope.
我这叫...出色
What I am...is good.
你和你的消防员伙计们绝对想不到 在季后赛...
And you and the rest of your firemen buddies aren't gonna know what hit you...
被谁迎头痛击了 纽约警局将会是今年的冠军
at the playoffs 'cause NYPD is gonna take it this year.
我告诉过他们男女混合的 棒球联赛不是什么好主意
Hey,I told them a coed baseball league was a bad idea.
Bonasera
Bonasera.
Stella
Stella.
你不是在去华盛顿作证的路上?
I thought you were supposed to be on your way to Washington to testify.
没错 但飞机上死人了 我的旅行计划变更了
I was,but a male DB changed my flight plans.
什么?
What?
死者伪装成一名空警
Yeah,the vic appears to have been posing as an air marshal.
他戴着真警徽 但没有身份证 枪也被人拿走了
He's got a badge that's legit,but no ID and an empty holster.
枪去哪里了?
Where's the gun?
我要知道就好了
Wish I could answer that.
你有听到其他的...
You hearing anything about...
劫机事件吗?
any other hijackings?
不 没有
No,no,nothing.
Mac 如果这是有组织犯罪 我们肯定已听到风声了
Mac,if this was organized,we'd have heard something.
除非这是第一起
Unless we're the first.
我把死者的指纹传回实验室了
I sent a set of the vic's prints to the lab.
Lindsay正在查他的身份
Have Lindsay find out who he is.
Stella 追查James Turner的背景
And Stella,hunt down everything you can on a James Turner.
他是嫌疑人?
He a suspect?
还不清楚
I don't know yet.
不过半小时后 我可能会知道
But in the next half hour,I just might find out.
那时候我们就落地了
That's when we land.
把所有人都叫到肯尼迪机场来 找一个停机棚
So,get everyone over to J,secure a hangar,
告诉他们飞机就是犯罪现场
and tell them I'm coming in with a crime scene.
查到他身份吗 Lindsay?
This is a positive ID,Lindsay?
死者名叫Anton Greenway
Your victim's name is Anton Greenway.
他就是假空警
He's your fake air marshal.
他昨天刚逃脱了法庭监管
Get this. He escaped from custody yesterday.
他因为三次累犯 将去辛辛监狱 服终身监禁
He was a three-striker headed to Sing Sing for a life stretch,
从法院的二楼跳窗逃跑了
and he jumped out of a second floor courtroom window.
他犯了什么罪?
Convicted of?
走私 贩毒
smuggling,dealing.
他之前受雇于大西洋美景航空 在肯尼迪机场工作过
He used to work at JFK as an employee for Atlantic Vista Airways,
所以他对飞机和机场很熟悉
so he knew his way around airplanes and airports.
警徽的真正主人呢?
What about the owner of the badge?
找到Roger Stockwell在哪儿了吗?
You been able to locate Roger Stockwell yet?
空警的指挥官说Stockwell 昨晚住在一家机场旅馆里
The director for the air marshals said Stockwell was staying at an airport hotel last night,
但他今早并未到地勤处报道
but he never checked in with the field office this morning.
Danny和Flack正赶往真空警住的旅馆
Danny and Flack are on their way to the real air marshal's hotel.
Roger Stockwell 纽约警察
Roger Stockwell,NYPD.
Stockwell先生 我们需要和你谈谈
Mr. Stockwell,we need to talk to you,sir.
打开
Open it.
那就是我们的空警
There's our air marshal.
看来他结账结得有点早了
Looks like he checked out early.
这个家伙可是被痛扁了一顿
This guy's been beat up pretty good.
脸上有淤伤 手臂上有防卫伤
Bruising on his face,defensive bruises on his arm.
无强行进入痕迹 但看来他结结实实干过一架
No sign of forced entry,but it does looks like he put up one hell of a fight.
从几时起清洁工开始用宽胶带了?
Since when do,uh,housekeepers use duct tape?
我猜从用它们包裹 点50口径的"沙漠之鹰"开始
I'm guessing since they started packing Desert Eagle .50s.
这门大炮火力够猛
That cannon packs quite a punch.
是啊 但旅馆住客和员工都没有 报警说听到枪响
Yeah,only there were no reports of gunshots from hotel guests or employees.
是的
Right.
训练有素又有武器的空警 怎会被人一枪正中眉心的?
So,how does a highly trained and armed air marshal take one between the eyes,
而且还没人听到?
and nobody hears anything?
他的头部伤口上有东西
Got something in his head wound.
你是说 除了那颗大口径的子弹?
You mean,besides the large caliber bullet?
白色纤维
White fibers.
看起来那边还有更多
Looks like there's some more of it over there.
哇
Boom.
这里有什么发现?
What have we got here?
这能算一个目击证人吗?
Can I get a witness?
嘿 你好
Well,hello there.
绒毛上有弹孔还有火药灼烧痕迹
Bullet hole and powder burns in the fur.
这可能就是没人听到枪响的原因
This might be why nobody heard anything.
随手抓来的消音器
An improvised silencer.
这里还有更多
There's some more,uh,trace here,too.
凶手的?
Killer's?
这种杂色粗毛不是人类的毛发
The variegated color and the coarseness suggest that it's not human.
似乎也不是这只熊猫的
And it doesn't appear to be from the panda.
也许这头熊有个伙伴
Maybe the bear has a friend.
这也可能是凶手进屋的方法
This also could be how the killer got in the room.
快递
Delivery.
你送错房间了
You got the wrong room.
是说102的啊
Says,102.
Roger Stockwell?
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
女士们先生们 请保持冷静
Ladies and gentlemen,please remain calm.
我们马上就可以下飞机了
We'll be deplaning momentarily.
请坐在位子上 保持冷静
Please remain seated and stay calm.
女士们先生们 请注意
Ladies and gentlemen,can I have your attention,please?
我叫Mac Taylor
My name is Mac Taylor.
我是纽约犯罪实验室的警探
I'm a detective with the New York Crime Lab.
起飞不久后 机上即发生了谋杀案
A murder was committed on this plane shortly after takeoff.
我们需要你们的通力合作
We'll need your full cooperation with our investigation.
在您下飞机后 请听从警官和探员的指挥
When you deplane,please follow the instructions of the officers and the agents.
我们将从您开始 先生
We're going to start with you,sir.
出什么事了?
What's going on?
请慢慢离开您的座位
Out of your seat slowly,please.
我什么都没做过
I didn't do anything.
慢慢的 只要跟着我就好了
Slowly. Come on. Just follow me.
我...我...
I... I...
跟这位警官走
Go with this officer.
剩下的人一个跟着一个走 从前排开始
Get the rest of them off one by one,starting with the front row.
国土安全局和联邦航空局相信 这次谋杀案是起孤立事件
Homeland Security and FAA believe that this murder was an isolated incident.
只要不撇下他们 他们很乐意让你当指挥
They're willing to let you take the lead so long as they're kept in the loop.
很好 我希望搜查下每位旅客 收集所有人的DNA和指纹
Good. I want each passenger searched. Collect DNA and prints.
唯一没干这件事的人 就是坐我旁边的那位
The only one I know didn't do it was the guy in the seat next to me.
Mac 没有搜查令我们不能那么做
Mac,we can't do any of that without a warrant,
而要拿到搜查令 我们需要可信的理由
and in order to get a warrant, we need probable cause.
理由就是谋杀 他们中有一个就是凶手
The cause is murder,and one of them is our killer.
我知道 我争辩过这一点
I know. I argued that point.
基本上 我们能做的就是 搜查旅客行李并要求他们合作
Basically,all we can do is search the passengers' carry-on luggage and ask for their cooperation.
如果他们拒绝...
If they refuse...
我们就得让他们走
We have to let them go.
对了 我们还不能拘留他们超过24小时
Right,and we can't detain them for more than 24 hours.
除非在那之前我们找到证据 锁定一个疑犯 不然他们都能走
So unless we find evidence to hold a suspect before then,they all walk.
现在 国土安全局的人要询问乘客了
Now,Homeland Security's going to question the passengers.
我们就去找证据
We're gonna check for evidence.
不好意思
Excuse me.
Hawkes 飞机上有具尸体
Hawkes,there's a body on the plane.
而且时间很紧 我去检查
And the clock's ticking. I'm on it.
Adam 我希望你搜一下垃圾箱
Adam,I want you to search the waste receptacles.
送餐车 走道 洗手间
Food service,walkways,lavatories.
任何凶手可以藏凶器和空警枪的地方
Any place the killer could have hidden the murder weapon and the air marshal's gun.
了解
Done.
Flack查了下疑犯 James Turner
Flack ran your suspect,James Turner.
他用现金买的单程票
He paid cash for a one-way ticket.
无托运行李 也没预定华盛顿的旅馆 也没有家在那里
Didn't check luggage,and didn't book a hotel room in Washington,DC,and doesn't live there.
那么他干嘛乘飞机呢?
So,why was he on the plane?
我怎么旅行根本与你无关
It's none of your business how I travel.
事实上 和我有关
Actually,it is.
你乘坐的飞机上发生了谋杀案 而你的衬衫上有血迹 Turner先生
You were on a flight where a murder was committed,and there's blood on your shirt,Mr. Turner.
看来你今天也没刮胡子
Doesn't look like you shaved today.
我不知道那是怎么弄上去的
I don't know how that got there.
等下 我是疑犯?
Wait. Am I a suspect?
你是否介意移步去那边的帐篷 然后脱掉自己的衣服?
Would you mind stepping over that tent and removing your clothes,please?
是的 是的 我介意
Yeah. Yeah,I do mind.
好吧
Okay.
我们就要来硬的了
We'll do this the hard way.
我们会给很多人打很多电话
We're gonna make a lot of phone calls to a lot of people,
会有人告诉我一些 你不想让我听到的事
and somebody's gonna tell me something you don't want me to hear.
听着 我在华盛顿有家庭
Look,I got a family in DC.
第二个家
A second family.
大老婆不知道
First wife doesn't know.
那是 唔...
It's,uh...
那很复杂 但我不是坏人 我发誓
It's complicated,but I'm not a bad guy,I swear.
回答错误 Turner先生
Wrong answer,Mr. Turner.
你应该解释一下 血迹是怎么弄到衬衫上的
What you should be explaining is how that blood got on your shirt,
发誓你没杀了机上的那个人
and swearing you didn't kill the guy on that plane.
我再要求你一次
I'm going to ask you one more time.
脱了你的衣服
Remove your clothing.
警官 陪他过去
Officer,escort him.
那么 你怎么想?
So,what do you think?
我们很快就能知道了
We'll know soon enough.
受害者流血过多而死
Vic bled out.
在颈部 是单独的刺入伤
A single stab wound to the neck.
血迹喷射情况说明 当时他很可能背靠墙站着
Spatter indicates he was most likely standing with his back to the wall.
然后转了个身 在倒下前动脉血喷散
He then spun around,leaving arterial spray before he collapsed.
我在水龙头上找到了血迹
I've got blood on the faucet.
看起来凶手进来清洗过
Looks like our killer came in here to clean up.
他回过道时可能留下一点点血迹
He could've left a latent blood trail on his way down the aisle.
也许会告诉我们他坐在哪里
Might tell us where he sat.
我去拿灯
I'll get the lights.
很多痕迹
Lot of trace.
定了旅馆房间 和上百号人粘乎一天 却忘了要客房服务
Take a hotel room,stick a couple of hundred people in there a day,forget about maid service.
这里能找到所有能想到的污点类型
We got every type of stain imaginable.
却没有血迹
No blood.
血迹只停留在第二个洗手间
Blood trail goes cold in the second bathroom.
你知道他们是怎么说吗
You know what they say.
甲之垃圾 乙之物证
One man's trash is another man's evidence pile.
你发现了什么?
What did you find?
空警的Sig枪 (瑞士SIG公司研制的枪 多为警用)
Air marshal's Sig.
从犯罪现场洗手间的垃圾堆底部收集来的
Bottom of the lav trash across from the crime scene.
为什么从枪套里拿出枪但却没用?
Why remove the gun from the holster and not use it?
也许凶手没有机会
Maybe our killer didn't get the chance.
他发现飞机掉头开了 受了惊吓就把枪扔了
You know,he found out the airplane was turning around,he got spooked and ditched the gun.
发现尸体后 没人进过洗手间
No one went into the bathroom after the body was discovered.
枪一定是谋杀发生前 或刚发生就被丢弃的
The gun had to have been dumped before or right after the murder.
有什么可以用作凶器的?
Anything that could have been used for a murder weapon?
还没有 除非你知道如何用这个来杀人
Nothing yet,unless you know how to kill a man with this.
那污水箱呢?
What about the waste tank?
凶器可能淹在水里
Weapon could have been flushed.
唔 你...你想我处理马桶?
Uh,you...uh,you want me to process the toilets?
你向我要求多参加外勤的 Adam
You asked for more field work,Adam.
去吧
Get to it.
我恨大粪
I hate poop.
逃亡者 Greenway需要离开这座城市
Okay,our fugitive,Greenway,needs to get out of the city,
所以他扮作一个空警 用Stockwell的枪和警徽登机
so he poses as an air marshal,boards a plane using Stockwell's gun and badge.
另一名乘客杀了他 没用枪 还把枪扔进垃圾桶了
Another passenger kills him,doesn't take the gun,and instead tosses it in the trash.
那说不通啊
Which doesn't make any sense.
杀空警夺他枪的唯一理由 就是要劫机
I mean,the only reason to kill an air marshal and take his gun is to hijack the plane.
但那种事却没发生
And that didn't happen.
也许凶手知道空警是个冒牌货
Maybe our killer knew the air marshal wasn't the air marshal.
那就是说 是出于其它原因
Well,that would mean that it's about something else.
或者...也许这个能回答这个问题
Or... maybe this can help us answer that.
告诉我你找到了凶器
Oh,tell me you found the murder weapon.
救生衣?
Life vest?
想像一下大约25万加元
Try about 250 thou Canadian.
分成5捆
Five bundles.
还有之前没找到的 空警的身份证和工作证
And the air marshal's missing ID and credential.
还有血迹
Blood.
如果这袋上的血是受害人的 那就是凶手在行凶后碰过这袋子
The blood on this pouch matches our vic,it means the killer touched it after committing murder.
他拿了钱和证件 然后把它们藏了起来
He takes the money and ID and hides them.
藏钱我理解 但为什么要藏证件?
I get the money,but why hide the ID?
混淆视线 拖延确认死者身份的时间
To throw us off and delay ID'ing the vic.
如果只有警徽和失踪的枪 我们会以为是劫机
If all we had was the badge and missing gun,then we'd be thinking it was a hijacking,
而不会猜到真相
instead of what it really might be.
三万尺高空中一场搞砸了的抢劫
A robbery gone bad at 30,000 feet.
真正的空警 Roger Stockwell 在倒地前就停止了呼吸
Your real air marshal,Roger Stockwell,was dead before he hit the hotel room floor.
被凶案现场找到的点50口径手枪 击中头部
Shot in the head with the .50 caliber recovered at the crime scene.
自卫造成的瘀痕?
Defensive bruising?
是Greenway 机上死者的杰作
Mr. Greenway,your airplane vic,can take credit for that.
正是他的拳头造成了 Stockwell下巴上的瘀痕
I was able to match his fist to the subdermal bruising on Stockwell's jaw.
这就确定了Stockwell和Greenway 曾干过一架
So that confirms that Stockwell and Greenway got in a fight.
Greenway身上的瘀伤是在饭店 而不是飞机厕所里的纠缠造成的
So,Greenway's bruising came from the hotel and not from the struggle in the airplane laboratory with his killer.
完全正确
Exactly.
还有一个疑点
And one mystery still remains.
猜猜正选凶器吗?
Care to take a stab at our murder weapon of choice?
可以确定凶器没有锋利的边刃
Well,definitely wasn't a fine-edged instrument.
这些组织看上去像是被撕裂 而不是被割破的
The tissue looks torn and not cut.
不错
Very good.
这里有些提示
Well,here's a clue.
下颚骨这里有两个特殊印迹
There are two unique marks on the mandible here.
棘手的难题
That's a tough one.
凶器是什么?
What's the murder weapon?
我不知道
I don't know.
从来没见过这样的
Never seen anything like this.
我把这难题留给你了
I'm leaving this one for you.
我要拿他下颚骨 浇铸一个模型
So,I'm gonna need his jawbone to make a mold.
看是否能找出和这些印记匹配的凶器
See if I can match a possible murder weapon out of those marks.
我还在他手上发现了保险套润滑剂 还有杀精剂的痕迹
I also found traces of condom lubricant and spermicide on his hand.
在进我的"非高级俱乐部"前 死者加入了"高空爽"俱乐部
(指在几千英尺高的飞机上做爱的行为)
Your vic may have joined the Mile-High Club before ending up in my not-so-exclusive one.
当然 他也可能是在上飞机前做的
Of course he could have had sex just prior to boarding.
但这样就不够刺激了
But that's not very exciting.
DNA呢 Sid?
Any DNA,Sid?
没 没有那个保险套 我无法告诉你更多的信息
No,and without that condom,I can't tell you much more than that.
除了他左手上的那个
Well,except for what's on his left hand there.
是什么? 字迹?
What's this? Writing?
呃 我在洗尸体时发现的
Yes,uh,I found it when I washed the body.
I-K-E-L-I-M-M
I-K-E-L-I-M-M.
好吧 我去语言文字数据库查一下
All right,I'll run it through a language database.
看看能否找到它的意思
See if I get any hits.
一定是用某种消不去的墨水写的
Must be some kind of indelible ink.
不论是什么 他一定不想忘了它
Whatever it is,he didn't want to forget it.
航空公司正送机组成员的衣服来
Airline's sending in the suits.
没和律师谈之前 他们不让我们 提取任何机组人员的样本
They won't let any of the crew members give us a reference sample until they each talk to a lawyer.
已经排除了Ed
Already eliminated Ed.
我可以排除机长和副驾驶员
I can eliminate the captain and the copilot.
谋杀发生前他们没离开过驾驶舱
They never left the cockpit before the murder.
国土安全局正再次和所有女乘客谈话
Homeland Security's talking to all the women passengers again.
但我有个问题
But let me ask you this.
如果有人和受害者做爱了 为什么完事后要杀了他?
If one of them had sex with our vic,why kill him afterwards?
众所周知 南方黒寡妇蜘蛛 在交配后会杀了雄蜘蛛
Southern black widow spider is known for eating the male after mating.
起码 它们面带微笑地死去
Well,at least they go out with a smile on their face.
"高空爽"俱乐部推测的唯一不足是
The only problem with the Mile-High Club theory is that
受害者可能在登机前做的爱
the vic could have had sex before he got on the plane.
没有证据证明那发生在飞机厕所里
There's no evidence that proves it happened in the lavatory.
我打赌是Turner干的
My money's on Turner.
别信重婚的家伙
Don't trust a guy who's got two families.
别下这个注
Don't make that bet.
DNA测试结果
DNA results.
他衬衫上的血迹不是受害者的
Blood on his shirt didn't match the vic.
是他自己的
Turned out to be his own.
好吧
Okay.
那还有谁值得怀疑呢?
So who else do we like for this?
没有证据的话?
Without evidence?
所有人
All of them.
空警房间里宽胶布上的指纹
Prints on the duct tape from the air marshal's hotel room
属于枪手/假空警Anton Greenway
were a match to our shooter-slash-fake air marshal-- Anton Greenway.
目前 我认为他最初计划是 绑起空警 偷他的证件
Now,I think his plan was to just tie up Stockwell and steal his credentials.
但他带了把枪
But he brought a gun.
拿来吓唬人的
Show of force.
看看这些证据 胶布 扭打的迹象
I mean,look at the evidence: there's the tape; the fact that there was a struggle;
尸体的位置远离门边
position of the body away from the door.
因为Stockwell反抗了
So Stockwell fought back.
Greenway觉得没了选择 只得开枪
Greenway felt had no choice but to use the gun.
对的
Right.
你查得怎样?
How about you?
我查遍了每一种语言文字数据库
I have run these letters through every language database.
这些字母在一起不是一个词
It's not a word.
不是电话号码
It's not a phone number.
看 如果我放大的话 你可以看出 "I"实际上不是字母"I"
See,if I zoom in,you can see that the "I"s-- they're not actually "I"s.
它们都是数字"1"
They're each the number 1.
是个代码
It's a code.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
或许它们是全球定位系统的座标
Maybe they're GPS coordinates.
没错 刚好7位字符
Exactly. Seven digits.
度数和十进制马表
Degrees and decimal minutes.
好嘞 来了
Okay,here we go.
蒙特利尔的圣安德鲁斯机场
St. Andrews Air Field. Montreal.
好像废弃了的
Looks abandoned.
假证件 枪 加元
Fake ID. Gun. Canadian money.
受害者不是想走私
Our vic wasn't smuggling.
他是想劫机后逃往加拿大
He was gonna hijack that plane and escape to Canada.
但如果他想去加拿大 为什么不乘直飞航班呢?
But if he wanted to get to Canada,why not just take a direct flight?
因为 即便是美国空警 也得接受加拿大海关检查
Well,being a US air marshal doesn't mean you're excluded from having to pass through Canadian customs.
他除了劫机没有别的选择
He had no choice but to hijack a plane.
但有人在他这么干前杀了他
But somebody killed him before he could do it.
是谁杀了劫机犯 又回到座位上 安心看机上播放的电影呢?
Who kills a hijacker and then returns back to their seat to watch the in-flight movie?
这就是Anton Greenway在机上穿的外套
This was the suit jacket our victim Anton Greenway was wearing on the airplane.
就像普通的成衣一样 是吧?
Yeah. And it looks like a regular jacket just off the rack,right?
对
Right.
错了
Wrong.
是度身定制的
Custom job.
看看
Take a look.
在衣服里找到这些
Found these in Layout.
隐藏的口袋 手工缝制在衬垫里
Hidden pockets hand-stitched into the liner.
Greenway曾是个毒品走私犯
Greenway was a drug smuggler.
是的 但这次 我想他走私了别的
Yeah,but I think this time he was carrying something else.
25万 装进这些口袋 刚好
The 250K fits perfectly into the pockets.
这就是他如何把现金带上飞机的
That's got to be how he got the cash on the plane.
偷来的空警警徽就是他过安检时 不被发现的法宝
And the stolen air marshal badge was his guaranteed ticket through security without it being discovered.
但凶手行凶后拿走了钱
But the killer moved the cash after the murder.
所以 要么他知道Greenway身上有钱 要么就是无意中发现的
So either he knew Greenway had the money on him or he found it by accident.
对 他知道飞机降落后 他不能把钱带下飞机
Yeah,and he knew he couldn't take it off the plane when it landed
我们或许会发觉他身上有钱 把他和谋杀案联系起来
because we might find it on him and connect him to the murder.
说得通 只是 是谁干的呢?
Well,it works. Only who are we talking about here?
我还有40个嫌疑人要排除 却只有这些推测
I've got 40 suspects left and only theories.
我还在外套上发现了可卡因 还有不属于人类的毛发
Well,I did discover traces of cocaine and nonhuman hair on the jacket.
这毛和Danny在饭店房间发现的吻合
Now,the hair's a match to the one Danny found in the hotel room.
我无法告诉你 它是哪里来的 但可以告诉你 这是根美洲豹的毛
Can't tell you where it came from, but I can tell you that it's leopard.
美洲豹? Greenway昨天前都在被拘押中
Leopard? Greenway was in controlled custody up until yesterday.
我不信他在逃跑和杀人间 还顺道去了趟动物园
I doubt he made a stop at the zoo between his escape and committing murder.
我认为Greenway有个同伙
I think Greenway had a partner.
这是场双簧?
This was a two-man show?
看上去像是
It's looking that way.
我刚检查完在旅馆用来杀空警的 "沙漠之鹰"手枪
I just finished processing the Desert Eagle that was used to kill the air marshal at the hotel.
序列号一早没了
Serial number is long gone.
用酸洗掉的
Acid-washed.
枪的其他部分也擦干净了
Rest of the gun wiped clean.
百密一疏
Almost.
枪手忘了擦弹夹
Shooter forgot to wipe down the magazine.
在AFIS数据库找到了这枚掌纹的所有者
Ran the palm print through AFIS and I got a hit.
他叫Terrence Davis
His name is Terrence Davis.
在市中心开了家俱乐部
Manages a club downtown. Okay?
但在做正经生意前 他在禁药进出口业小有名气
But before he went legit,he made a name for himself in the import-export business
直到缉毒署迫使他关张
until the DEA forced him to retire. Okay?
他在Rikers监狱待了5年
He did five years in Rikers.
被捕前 他在大西洋美景航空公司 负责搬运装卸行李
Prior to the arrest,he worked baggage at Atlantic Vista Airways.
Greenway也做过这个活
Same job Greenway had.
而且两人是同时同地工作
Yeah,and they worked there at the same time.
Terrence Davis 他的名字不在旅客名单上
Terrence Davis-- his name's not on the flight manifest.
如果他们是同伙 为什么他们不在同一架飞机上?
If they're partners,how come they weren't on the same plane?
我想 我们应该去问问他
I think we should ask him.
要么我是对半裸女郎过敏 要么这里有只貓
Either allergic to half-naked women or there's a cat in here.
这儿是有只猫
There's a cat in here.
那是我们要找的Terrence Davis
There's our boy Terrence Davis.
养了好大只猫
Big housecat.
就是这只大猫让我的酒吧火了
You could say she put this club on the map.
我对猫不大感冒
Not really into cats myself.
我猜猜 你们是警察?
Let me guess: you're more K-9?
你倒没看上去那么笨
Smarter than you look.
有何贵干 McGruff(警犬名)?
What can I do for you,McGruff?
因为我没什么心情
'Cause I'm seriously not in the mood.
也许到你办公室心情会好点
Maybe the mood's better in your office.
我可没在征询你意见
I'm not asking.
好吧 伙计 怎么回事?
Okay,guys,what's this about?
怎么回事? 是关于你搭档的事
What's this about? It's about your partner.
Anton Greenway
Anton Greenway.
当你为大西洋美景航空工作时
We know that you two moved into and blow out of baggage claim at JFK
你俩曾在肯尼迪机场行李领取处干过
while you worked for Atlantic Vista Airways.
陈年旧事了 老兄
Long time ago,man.
你们干嘛不提点新鲜的?
Aren't you up on current events?
说得没错
You know what? You're right.
我们有点落伍了
We're a little behind.
所以我们来找你谈谈
That's why we came to talk to you.
干嘛不告诉我们是谁杀的 Anton Greenway
Why don't you tell us who killed Anton Greenway.
Anton死了?
Anton's dead?
别装得好像刚知道似的
Don't play like this is new news.
我早就不玩这一招了 伙计
I don't have game like that no more,man.
那个瘾君子死了 跟我可没关系
That dope fiend is dead,it's nothing to do with me.
而且 他比瞎子开枪还疯狂
Besides,he was crazier than a blind gunfighter.
难怪他会去见阎王
Not surprise he met his demise.
也许你之所以不觉得惊讶 是因为你与此事有关
Maybe you're not so surprised because you had something to do with it.
Anton偷了空警的证件登机 然后在机上被杀
Anton was killed on a plane that he boarded using stolen air marshal credentials.
空警被人用"沙漠之鹰"杀了 上面都是你的指纹
An air marshal who was murdered with a Desert Eagle that had your prints all over it.
明白我什么意思了吧 T?
You see where I'm going with this,T?
你最后一次见到你哥们Anton 是什么时候?
When was the last time you saw your buddy Anton?
昨天
Yesterday.
几年来头回见到他
First time I seen him in years.
跟我们讲讲你们的大团聚
Tell us about the reunion.
听着 他找我是为了我给他点钱 好去买点大麻吸 就这样
Look,man,the game through 'cause I was holding some lettuce for him till he got out the joint. That's it.
他穿的外套呢?
What about the jacket he was wearing?
内衬缝上能偷运毒品口袋的那件
The one with the all the pockets sewn into it for smuggling dope.
金盆洗手好多年了
Retired years ago.
Anton来过 想要那件外套
Anton came by. He wanted it.
我说行 只要我不知情就成
I said cool,as long as I don't know nothing to do with nothing.
知道我意思吧?
You know what I mean?
回到有你指纹的点50口径枪上
Let's get back to the .50 then with your prints on it.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
听我说
Listen to me,T.
我可以控告你谋杀 证据确凿
I got a solid murder charge that I can hang around your neck.
找错人了
Wrong guy.
人不是我杀的
I didn't pull no trigger.
凶器上只有你的指纹
Your prints are the only ones on the weapon.
我不在乎你们有什么
I don't care what you got.
我没杀人
I didn't kill no one.
真的
Truth.
说得不错
Not bad.
但你的表现不会在陪审团前加分 因为它不会让你免于牢狱之灾
But I'd pull out some tears for the jury because that performance won't keep you out of jail.
走吧
Let's go.
我会带你走出前门
I'm taking you out the front door.
好了 伙计
All right,cool,man.
你们想因非法持枪罪逮捕我 没问题
Look,you want to arrest me for gun possession,cool.
但知道吗
But you know what?
事实是 我要把枪交给你们
Matter of fact,I'll give you the gun.
把手举起来 举起来!
Let me see those hands Now! Hands!
马上举起来!
Do it,now!
人渣
Scum.
我想帮那个蠢货 他却这样对我
I'd tried to help this fool and this is what he does.
不会枉惩好人的
No good deed goes unpunished.
你还是会因违反假释条例 非法持有那把枪而受罚
You're also going to take a hit for a parole violation for owning that gun.
设想一下你的处境
Assume the position.
Terrence Davis仍坚持他的说法
Terrence Davis is sticking to his story.
我们只能因非法持枪罪扣着他
We're still holding him on a gun charge,
但Roger Stockwell 那个空警被杀时 他有完美的不在场证明
but he's got a solid alibi for the time that Roger Stockwell,the air marshal,was killed.
你有什么发现?
What have you got?
这些是飞机上有可能被用作 谋杀凶器的所有东西
Well,this is everything from the airplane that could've conceivably been used as a murder weapon.
我都拿来做了血液检测 查DNA
I ran it all for blood and DNA.
没找到吻合的
No hits.
不奇怪
Doesn't surprise me.
我们知道凶手洗手了
We know that our killer washed up.
他大概把凶器也洗了
He probably cleaned the weapon too.
没错 所以唯一能确定凶器的方法 就是找出...
Right. So the only way for us to ID the weapon is to figure out
是什么物体造成了死者下颌骨上的 特殊印记
what made these distinctive marks in the vic's jaw.
好吧 我们要找一个两叉的武器
Okay. So we're looking for a two-pronged weapon.
看看这些东西能造成怎样的损伤
Let's see what kind of damage these guys can do.
他们带着这些怎么登上飞机?
How do people get on board with this stuff?
我的牙膏都给没收了
I had my toothpaste confiscated.
不是我们要找的凶器
It's not our weapon.
我们要找个能刺得更深的东西
All right. We need to find something that would penetrate deeper.
所有的都试过了
We're running out of possibilities.
正好 我正找你们呢
Oh,good. I was looking for you guys.
老天哪 Adam
Oh,my God,Adam.
什么味儿?
What is that smell?
是...垃圾加上一点...厕所味儿
Oh,it's garbage and a little,uh...eau de toilet.
我说真的
Literally.
希望值得你这么拼命
I hope it was worth it.
好消息
Big time.
我想我找到了什么
I think I got something.
我在洗手间垃圾里找到了 这个避孕套...
The condom that I found,in the lavatory waste...
你找到了DNA
You got DNA.
没有 死者的套套浮在有毒废物 垃圾处理箱里
No way. The vic's love glove was found floating in a toxic waste dump.
但包装没被烧坏 包装上的口红印也好好的
But the wrapper survived the stew,and so did the the lipstick on the wrapper.
花了点时间 但我会找出颜色型号 以及生产厂家的
It took a little time,but I was able to narrow it down the shade and the manufacturer.
太棒了 做得好 Adam
Fantastic. Great work,Adam.
呃...我得去冲个澡
Yeah,uh,I...I should shower.
没错 是该洗个澡了
Yeah,yeah. You do that.
Terrence 我们现在没法交流
Well,I think what we have here is a failure to communicate,Terrence.
我在说 可你没在听
I'm talking,but you ain't listening.
我只是没感觉 Flack
I'm just not feeling,Flack.
也许你对这个有感觉
Well,maybe you'll feel this.
记得那把上面满是你指纹的枪吗?
Remember that defaced firearm with your prints all over the magazine,
Anton从你酒吧拿走的那把
the one Anton swiped from the club?
那把枪被用来杀了一名联邦探员
It was used to kill a federal agent.
我要是把消息通知联邦法警局 你就至少蹲十年牢
Now if I let this go federal,you're gonna do at least ten years up there.
但是 如果我不报上去 你大概就用不着受牢狱之灾
However,if I keep it local,you probably won't do any real jail time.
不上报...
Local...
意味着有附加条件 对吧?
that means strings attached,right?
你开着城里最热门的夜店
You manage the hottest club in the city.
你说你金盆洗手了 但我相信你对道上的事还是了若指掌
You say you're out of the life,but I'm sure you keep your ear to the rail.
我听到些消息
I hear things.
我希望听到你了解的消息
I want to hear what you hear.
怎么让我脱罪?
How does it work?
你会被判重罪 和检察官达成辩诉交易...
You'll be charged with a felony,take a plea...
然后转为秘密线人将功赎罪
and work off your time as a confidential informant.
Terrence 过了这村可没那店了
Now,this is a very limited-time offer,Terrence.
说的就是现在
Limited,in like right now.
地方检察官正等我消息呢
I got a DA waiting to hear from me.
要你一句话
I need a decision.
自打见你第一面起 就知道我们会成为朋友
The minute I met you,I knew we'd be friends.
很好
Excellent.
没时间了
Clock ran out.
我还需要点时间
I need more time.
我没法再扣着他们了
I got nothing to hold them on.
我们没办法了
It's out of our hands.
其中一人昨天杀了人 现在我们把他们放了
One of these people committed murder yesterday and we're letting them go.
国安局也不想放人 不过我们都没得选
Homeland Security doesn't like it anymore than we do,but none of us have a choice here.
把衣服还我
I want my clothes back.
调查结束后 犯罪实验室会返还的
They'll be released from the crime lab when the investigation's over.
等着我律师联系你吧
You're going to hear from my attorney.
上车去
Get on the bus.
你去哪儿?
Where you going?
我不会就这么让凶手跑了的
I'm not in the business of letting killers go.
Taylor警探
Detective Taylor.
Bonasera警探在线上等你
I've got Detective Bonasera on the line for you.
有什么发现 Stella?
What have you got,Stella?
一枚唇印 可能跟其中一名女性嫌犯相吻合
A lipstick stain. We might be able to match it to one of our female suspects.
我把空姐Nina的口红比较后发现
Now,I ran it by the lipstick that you took off of Nina the flight attendant.
不相符
No match.
他们都有嫌疑 搜查令马上就下来
Everyone else is in play,and warrants are on their way.
他们都被放了
They're gone.
人都走了
They're all gone.
我们只能把他们放了
We had to cut them loose.
好的 谢谢
Good,thanks.
大巴上的人都下光了
The bus just dropped everybody off.
我现在派人去把女乘客和机组成员 给找回来
Now I got guys out there ready to round up all the female passengers and crew members and bring them back,
不过要花几小时
but it's going to taka couple hours.
到时她肯定早就跑了
She could be long gone by then.
有什么发现 医生?
What do you got,Doc?
好消息 我用X荧光射线检测了 Greenway的下颌骨
Good news. I put the XRF to Greenway's jawbone,
在印记里发现了些镀铜和镍的痕迹 是从凶器上带过去的
and I found traces of brass and nickel plating in the marks made by our murder weapon.
我查了下 发现镀镍工艺常被用在 奖杯 徽章和首饰里
I did a little research,and found that nickel plating is commonly used in trophies,badges,jewelry.
但从机上没收的那些东西里 没有与之吻合的
But there was nothing confiscated from the plane that matches our murder weapon.
你在想什么 Mac?
What are you thinking,Mac?
还有翼型章
And wings.
空乘的翼型章
Flight attendant's wings.
是金属做的 边缘也够锋利...
They are made from metal,and the edges would be more than sharp enough...
可以刺透皮肤
to puncture the skin.
Hawkes 给我发一张下颌骨的照片
Hawkes,send me a picture of that jawbone.
马上
It's on its way.
徽章的尖端与死者下颌的印记吻合
The points of the wing are a match to the marks in the vic's jaw.
看来找到凶器了
Looks like you found the murder weapon.
还有凶手
And our murderer.
看看这些空乘
Look at the flight attendants.
他们下飞机时 我们拍了照 而Susan...
We took their photos as they came off the plane,and Susan...
是唯一没有佩戴翼型章的
is the only one not wearing her wings.
太好了
Oops.
我刚跟航空公司通过电话 Mac
I just got off the phone with the airline,Mac.
对方说她刚用自己的特权 搭上了去巴黎的班机
The airline rep said she used her privileges to hop a flight to Paris,
三分钟内从50号门起飞
that leaves out of Gate 50 in three minutes.
她要跑了
She's running.
最后一遍广播 飞往巴黎的大西洋 美景航空公司的1256航班即将起飞
Last call for Atlantic Vista Airways Flight 1256 departing for Paris.
所有乘客应当立刻登机
All passengers should be on board at this time.
你们不能下去
You can't go down there.
这违反联邦航空局规定...
It's against FAA...
走吧
Let's go.
我实验室的人在缝里找到了 Anton Greenway的血
My lab found Anton Greenway's blood in the crevices.
他想劫机
He was going to hijack the plane.
我应当保护乘客
I should be commended for protecting the passengers.
只是你没来领功
Only you didn't come forward to take credit.
我吓坏了 机上可能还有一名劫机犯
I was scared. There could've been another hijacker on the plane.
没有别人了 你知道的
There wasn't,and you knew that.
因为你认识Anton
because you knew Anton.
他走私毒品那阵 你们都在大西洋美景航空工作
You both worked at Atlantic Vista Airways at the same time,while he was smuggling drugs.
如果他也在那家航空公司工作 那只是巧合
If he worked at that airline,it was a coincidence.
昨天你把25万美元兑换成加拿大元
Yesterday,you converted a quarter-million US dollars into Canadian money.
跟Anton藏在身上外套里 偷运上机的数目一样
The exact amount Anton smuggled on board inside the jacket he was wearing.
搜查令马上就到
I have a warrant on the way.
我会把你的口红跟找到的 避孕套上的唇印进行比对
I'm going to match your lipstick to the condom wrapper we found.
我们可以继续在这兜圈子 Susan 但前方已经没路了
We can continue to dance here,Susan,but the song's over.
我爱他 你知道吗?
I loved him,you know?
你在帮他逃跑...
And you were helping him escape...
只是出了岔子
only something went wrong.
前一秒 是他情人...
One minute you're his lover...
后一秒 杀了他
the next,his killer.
他做了什么?
What did he do?
他杀了那个空警
He murdered that air marshal.
他本来只该把他绑起来 抢了警徽 证件就好
He was only supposed to tie him up and rob him.
我们是那么说好的
That's what we agreed to.
他还改变了其他什么计划?
What other plans did he change?
一切都变了
Everything.
他拿枪抵着我的脖子 说他不想去华盛顿
He put a gun up to my neck and told me he didn't want to go to DC.
他想让飞机飞到加拿大
He wanted the plane to fly to Canada.
我同意帮他逃出纽约
I agreed to help him get out of New York.
我不同意劫持一架满载无辜者的飞机
I didn't agree to take over an airplane filled with innocent people.
听我说
Listen to me.
我要逃出美国
I've got to get out of the country.
不 我告诉过你我们可以在着陆后 再搭别的飞机
No. I told you we can take another plane when we land.
别说了!
Forget it!
带我去驾驶室 其他的我来做
Just get me to the cockpit and I'll do the rest.
你疯了吗? 别说了
Are you crazy? Forget it.
我们不是这样说的
This isn't what we talked about.
Susan 没有你 我去不了驾驶室
Susan,I can't get into the cockpit without your help.
照做 不然就去死
Do it or you die.
那时 你只有两条路可走: 站出来 阻止劫机
At that point,you had two choices: come forward,having prevented a hijacking,
或者 去拿钱
or go for the cash.
你选错了 Susan...
You made the wrong choice,Susan...
现在你作茧自缚了
and now you're grounded.